Save the Pine Bush, Inc.; Records apap125
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Save the Pine Bush, Inc. Records
1977-2001
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Save the Pine Bush, Inc.
apap125
8.87 cubic ft. and 2 oversize folders
Records of Save the Pine Bush, Inc., a non profit organization concerned with protecting the rare inland pine barrens sand dunes of the Capital District, known as the Albany Pine Bush, which are home to the Karner Blue Butterfly.
Administrative History
Save the Pine Bush Inc. (SPB), incorporated in 1978, is a non profit, volunteer organization dedicated to preserving the Albany Pine Bush. The Pine Bush is a rare ecosystem in New York State and the largest inland pine barrens sand dunes in the United States. The area is known to contain over 1,500 species of plants, over 300 species of vertebrate animals, and over 10,000 species of insects and other invertebrate animals [Save the Pine Bush Introduction to Save the Pine Bush, 2002. http://www.savethepinebush.org/Intro/Intro.html (18 July 2002)]. The rarest of these inhabitants is the Karner Blue Butterfly, listed on the New York State Endangered Species list in 1978 and the Federal Endangered Species list in 1992 [Save the Pine Bush Introduction to Save the Pine Bush, 2002. http://www.savethepinebush.org/Intro/Intro.html (18 July 2002)]. The Pine Bush is located in the heart of the Capital District, concentrated mostly between the cities of Albany and Schenectady. Office buildings and residential developments have played a role in reducing the once 25,600 acre area into 3,000 acres. Concerned with preserving the Pine Bush habitat, the organization, Save the Pine Bush formed to prevent development in the Pine Bush area by suing government agencies and developers, forcing these groups to follow state environmental preservation laws [Save the Pine Bush. Welcome to Save the Pine Bush, June 2002. http://www.savethepinebush.org (18 July 2002). How does Save the Pine Bush stop developers? May 2002. http://www.savethepinebush.org/Intro/How_does.html (18 July 2002)].
The group of advocates joined together in 1978 under the name "Friends of the Pine Bush" to protest the approval for four developments in the Pine Bush: the Dunes, Pinehurst, Pine Circle, and a development proposed by Charles Touhey impacts [Lynne Jackson. Save the Pine Bush Brief History and Summary, July 1996. http://www.savethepinebush.org/MoreArt/summary.html (18 July 2002)]. The approvals occurred after a public hearing that was poorly attended due to a snowstorm. Friends of the Pine Bush won its first court case in 1978 under the guidance of the lawyer Victor A. Lord by suing the City of Albany over the approval of the four developments. The court ruled in favor of the Pine Bush advocates, stating that the City's approval of these developments was invalid and that the City had to hold another public hearing before they could make a decision on whether to approve the construction of the developments. Another public hearing occurred and the developments in question were again approved. After the approval, the organization officially incorporated, taking the name "Save the Pine Bush" due to the fact that there was already a group registered under the name "Friends of the Pine Bush" Under the guidance of lawyer Dennis Kaufman, Save the Pine Bush was able to postpone the development construction by suing the Planning Board for not posting a bond to insure that improvements in the area such as streets and sewers, were completed as required by law impacts [Lynne Jackson. Save the Pine Bush Brief History and Summary, July 1996. http://www.savethepinebush.org/MoreArt/summary.html (18 July 2002)].
From 1979 to the present, Save the Pine Bush has been involved in a number of lawsuits, led by lawyer Lawrence B. Oliver, Jr. Many of the lawsuits involved violations of the State Environmental Quality Review Act (SEQRA) a law that requires municipalities to review housing developments, office complexes and other developments for their environmental impacts [Lynne Jackson. Save the Pine Bush Brief History and Summary, July 1996. http://www.savethepinebush.org/MoreArt/summary.html (18 July 2002)]. Lawsuits filed include the Madison Avenue Office Park Project, Willow Street, Karner Meadows, Karner Dunes Adventure Park, the Albany Interim Landfill, and the Pine Haven Estates [Series 5: Lawsuits and Challenges, Sub-series 1: Lawsuits. Boxes 1-19]. Several defendants listed in the lawsuits include the City of Albany, Town of Guilderland, developer Charles Touhey, and the Albany Pine Bush Preserve Commission. Active members of Save the Pine Bush have included Lynne Jackson, Rezsin Adams, John Wolcott, Gregory Bell, and Russell Ziemba.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the activities of Save the Pine Bush, Inc., a non profit organization concerned with protecting the rare inland pine barrens sand dunes of the Capital District, known as the Albany Pine Bush. The Pine Bush is the largest ecosystem of its kind and home to the Karner Blue Butterfly, which was placed on the Federal Endangered Species List in 1992.
Included in the collection are the records of three organizations concerned with environmental issues in the 1970s; the University at Albany's Protect Your Environment (PYE) student organization (1973-1975), People for the Pine Bush (1973-1975), and Citizen's For the Environment (CPE), based in Schenectady, New York (1974-1979). Lynne Jackson, one of Save the Pine Bush's founding members and the donor of the collection, was involved in all three of the organizations. The records of PYE and People of the Pine Bush are scarce, consisting mostly of the academic papers by Lynne Jackson, meeting minutes and notes. CPE records consist of meeting minutes, budgets, papers concerning the CPE recycling program, and environmental newsletters CPE and CPE president Linda Hitchcock subscribed to.
The Save the Pine Bush collection includes meeting minutes, agendas, grant proposals, fliers, and other materials from the years 1978-1980. The remainder and bulk of collection consists of litigation papers, Draft Environmental Impact Statements (DEIS), Final Environmental Impact Statements (FEIS), correspondence, Save the Pine Bush newsletters and activities announcements, maps, and Freedom of Information Act requested materials concerning various proposed development sites from the years 1978-2001. Earlier papers and lawsuits have the title of Friends of the Pine Bush, the name of the organization prior to incorporation.
A strength of the collection is the Save the Pine Bush Newsletters from 1978-1980 and 1989-2001,even though there is a significant gap of nine years. The collection is also strong in regards to litigation papers, including Notice of Petitions, Briefs, Affidavits, Memorandums of Law, and Appeals. Finally, the collection contains over 35 oversize maps and blueprints of proposed development sites.
The collection is weak in the day to day running of Save the Pine Bush after 1981, and excludes any financial papers discussing funding and expenses. Correspondence consist mostly of material collected through Freedom of Information Act requests rather then specific Save the Pine Bush correspondence.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Lynne Jackson in 2001.
Related Materials
Several collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives provide further information about the construction of Crossgates Mall and the Pine Bush including the records of Concerned Citizens Against Crossgates (APAP-057) and Crossgates Regional Shopping Mall Collection (APAP-067). A complete list of related collections is available at the subject guide for Conservation and the Environment.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Conservation and the Environment; Albany, New York; Environmental policy.; Environmental protection.; Environmental law -- United States -- Cases.; Environmental impact statements -- New York (State) -- Albany County.; Environmental impact statements -- New York (State) -- Schenectady County.; Ecology -- Pine Barrens (N.Y.); Pine Barrens (N.Y.); Adams, Rezsin.; Wolcott, John.; Hitchcock, Linda.; Bell, Gregory.; Ziemba, Russell.; Corporate Save the Pine Bush, Inc.; Protect Your Environment.; People for the Pine Bush.; Citizen’s Protecting the Environment.; Friends of the Pine Bush.
- Protect Your Environment/People For the Pine Bush, 1973-1975; 1; 0.2 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  Protect Your Environment was the environmental student organization formed at the University at Albany in early 1970s. People for the Pine Bush was a similar environmental organization, a precursor to Save the Pine Bush. The series is a collection of papers, articles, notes, and meeting minutes of both organizations through Lynne Jackson's involvement in the organization as a student at the University at Albany.
  Arrangement
  Organized alphabetically.
  - Arizona Highways, 1973 November (Box 1 (1-Protect Your Environment/People For the Pine Bush), Folder 1)
  - Moss Island Project, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Protect Your Environment/People For the Pine Bush), Folder 2)
  - "SUNYA Recycle", 1974-1976 (Box 1 (1-Protect Your Environment/People For the Pine Bush), Folder 3)
  - Articles, Notes, Meetings, Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 1 (1-Protect Your Environment/People For the Pine Bush), Folder 4)
  - "Exercise in Planning: Waterways", 1975 (Box 1 (1-Protect Your Environment/People For the Pine Bush), Folder 5)
- Citizens Protecting the Environment, 1974-1979; 2; 0.8 cubic ft.
  Prior to Save the Pine Bush, Inc., Lynne Jackson was actively involved in Citizen's Protecting the Environment (CPE) an environmental organization based in Schenectady, New York. The series includes CPE agendas and meeting minutes, brochures, budgets, correspondence, and papers concerning a recycling education class project. Also included are press releases and numerous newsletters from other organizations connected to environmental activism. Though there are a variety of organizations which produced newsletters represented in the collection, there is generally only one or two newsletters per group. One oversize box contains larger newsletters printed on newsprint.
  Organized by subject.
  - Agendas and Meeting Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 1)
  - Agendas and Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 2)
  - Agendas and Meeting Minutes, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 3)
  - Brochures, Undated (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 5)
  - By-Laws, Revised, Undated (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 8)
  - Employment Applications/Resumes, Undated (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 9)
  - Expenses and Income, 1974-1978 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 10)
  - Fundraising Events, 1976-1979 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 11)
  - Mailing Lists, Undated (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 12)
  - Membership Applications, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 13)
  - Project: Bottle Bill Legislation, Undated (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 14)
  - Project: Recycling Grant Proposal, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 15)
  - Project: Recycling Program, Local Education Effort, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 16)
    Includes Negatives.
  - Project: Recycling Program, Memorandum and Sample Letter of Solicitation, Undated (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 1)
  - Project: Recycling Program Volume Figures, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 2)
  - Public Relations, Public Service Announcements, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 3)
  - Senior AIDES Program, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 4)
  - Handbook, Energy on Film, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, HSPC Review, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Soil and Water Conservation, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, Capital District SUN DAY, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, North River Friends of Clearwater, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, ACEMC Newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady News, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, New York Environmental News (NYEN), 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, Region II in View, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, Cooperative Self Reliance Task Force, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, Environmental Planning Lobby, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, Safe Energy Coalition of New York State, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, Miscellaneous Newsletters and Fliers, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, 1976-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 18)
  - Schenectady Employment and Training Administration (SETA), Attendance Sheets, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 19)
  - SETA, Contracts, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 20)
  - SETA, Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (2-Citizens Protecting the Environment), Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, Clamshell Alliance News, Vol. 3 Nos. 5 and 6, 1979 (Oversized 3, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, Maine Land Advocate, Vol. 7, No. 1, 1979 (Oversized 3, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, NYS Environment, 1979 (Oversized 3, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Rappin' with SCAP, 1977 (Oversized 3, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 765 Hotline, 1977-1979 (Oversized 3, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Sunday Times, 1978 March (Oversized 3, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, The Waste Paper, 1979 (Oversized 3, Folder 7)
- Save the Pine Bush Newsletters and Activities, 1978-1980; 1989-2001; 3; 0.64 cubic ft.
  Series contains newsletters, monthly activities fliers, and press releases produced by Save the Pine Bush. Press releases date from 1978 to 1980. No newsletters are represented between 1981 to 1988. Monthly activities fliers begin with 1989.
  Organized chronologically.
  - Press Releases, 1978-1980 (Box 1 (3-Save the Pine Bush Newsletters and Activities), Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1978-1980 (Box 1 (3-Save the Pine Bush Newsletters and Activities), Folder 2)
  - Newsletters and Activities, 1989-1993 (Box 1 (3-Save the Pine Bush Newsletters and Activities), Folder 3)
  - Newsletters and Activities, 1994-2001 (Box 1 (3-Save the Pine Bush Newsletters and Activities), Folder 4)
- Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files, 1978-1981; 4; 0.2 cubic ft.
  Series contains agenda, meeting minutes, grants, by-laws, fliers, notes and drafts. Also included are a variety of miscellaneous papers. Some papers come from Friends of the Pine Bush, the original unincorporated name of the organization.
  The Laws, Statutes, and Regulations folder consists of photocopied papers from 1929-1979. The folder was compiled in 1979 and is organized under that date rather then the 1929 date.
  - Community Development Grants, 1979-1981 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - DEC Task Force, Environmental Base Analysis, 1979 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Friends of the Pine Bush and Save the Pine Bush, Agendas and Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Friends of the Pine Bush, By-Laws, Undated (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Laws, Statutes, and Regulations, 1929-1979 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - New Jersey Pine Barrens, 1978 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Proposed Legislative Bill, 1979 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Public Debate Announcements, 1979 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Save the Pine Bush Fliers, Undated (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 9)
  - Save the Pine Bush, Miscellaneous Papers, 1979; Undated (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 10)
  - Save the Pine Bush, Notes and Drafts, 1980 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - State Environmental Quality Review (SEQR) Regulations, 1978 (Box 1 (4-Save the Pine Bush Administrative Files), Folder 12)
- Lawsuits and Challenges, 1977-2000; 5; 7.03 cubic ft. and 2 oversize folders
  Series is broken into the sub-series Lawsuits and Challenges. The Lawsuits sub-series includes Draft Environmental Impact Statements (DEIS), Final Environmental Impact Statements (FEIS), Freedom of Information Act requested material (mostly photocopies and faxes of developer proposals and developer, city, or town correspondence), and litigation papers such as Notice of Petitions, Affidavits, Briefs, Memorandum of Law, and Appeals Claims. Early Lawsuits may have the name Friends of the Pine Bush, the original unincorporated name of the organization.
  Note: Box 9, Folder 7 contains photocopied local laws from 1970-1998. The information was compiled in 1998, so the folder is filed under that date rather then the 1970 date.
  Box 2, Folders 10-13 contain a small collection of material on the lawsuit filed by Concerned Citizens Against Crossgates against the construction of Crossgates Mall.
  The Challenges sub-series consists of the DEIS, FEIS, correspondence, zoning applications, articles and papers of the Golden Bear Family Golf Center proposed site. It also includes a number of development site proposals. All material excludes any litigation papers, for no lawsuits transpired.
  The series concludes with two oversize boxes and 2 oversize folders of maps and blueprints of development sites. Corresponding folders from Boxes 5, 9, 11, 20 and 21 are noted. Oversize boxes are organized by size, sub-series and then chronologically by development site. Map folders are organized by size and listed individually in box and folder list. Several maps consist of photocopied pieces of the original map which must be placed together.
  Alphabetical Listing of Lawsuits in Series 5:
  Albany Landfill Expansion, Boxes 5-7, 22, Folder 1.
  Albany Pine Bush Preserve Commission, Box 15.
  Columbia Circle, Boxes 13-14.
  Crossgates Mall, Box 3, Folders 10-13.
  Dunes and Pine Hurst, Box 3, Folders 1, 7-9.
  Karner Dunes Adventure Park, Boxes 18-19.
  Karner Meadows, Boxes 1-2.
  Karner Pines, Box 11, Folders 6-8.
  40 Karner Rd. and 300 Washington Ave. Extension, Box 11, Folder 1-5. Box 22, Folder 7.
  Loop Road, Box 12.
  Pine Haven Estates, Boxes 16-17.
  Madison Avenue Park, Box 4, Folders 1-6.
  Pine Circle, Box 3, Folders 1-6.
  State Employees Federal Credit Union, Box 8.
  Willow Street/Tera Court, Boxes 9-10, 22, Folders 2-6.
  Woodlands at Pine Ridge, Box 4, Folder 7.
  Organized by site location.
  - Lawsuits, 1977-2000; 5.1
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Property Values, 1967-1977 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 1)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Environmental Assessment, 1978 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 2)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Appendix on Behalf of Petitioners-Respondents, 1980 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 3)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Respondents-Interveners-Appellants Brief in Support to Leave for Appeal, 1980 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 4)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Brief Submitted on Behalf of Respondents-Appellants, 1982 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 5)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Submitted on Behalf of Respondents-Appellants, 1982 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 6)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Respondent-Interveners-Appellants Appendix, 1982 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 7)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Notice of Motion for Leave of Appeal, 1983 (Box 1 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 8)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 2 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 1)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Supplement to Final Environmental Impact Statement, 1985 (Box 2 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 2)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows Notice of Petition, 1986 (Box 2 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 3-4)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Appellant's Brief on Appeal, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 5)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Karner Meadows, Counterclaim, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 6)
    - Friends of the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Pine Circle, Dunes and Pinehurst, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 1)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Pine Circle, Testimony, 1979 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 2)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Pine Circle, Litigation, 1979 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 3)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Pine Circle, Notice of Motion, Affidavits, 1979 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 4)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Pine Circle, Order to Show Cause, 1979 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 5)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Pine Circle, Brief and Appendix on Behalf of Appellants, 1979 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 6)
    - Friends of the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Dunes and Pinehurst, Appeals, 1980-1982 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 7)
    - Friends of the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Dunes and Pinehurst, Maps and Development Progress Report, Undated (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 8)
    - Friends of the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Dunes and Pinehurst, Brief and Appendix on Behalf of Interveners-Respondents and Reply brief on Behalf of Appellants-Respondents, 1983 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 9)
    - Crossgates Mall, Fliers and News Clippings, 1978-1980 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 10)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. Pyramid Crossgates, Subpoenas, 1980 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 11)
    - Pyramid Crossgates Company, Notice of Motion, 1980 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 12)
    - Concerned Citizens Against Crossgates, Brief and Notice of Motion for Leave of Appeal, 1982-1983 (Box 3 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 13)
    - Save the Pine Bush vs. City of Albany, Madison Avenue Office Park, Verified Answer and Notice of Petition, 1985 (Box 4 (5-Lawsuits and Challenges), Folder 1)